With the mobile application, you log into
the account you previously created
on the pictotree.eu web app.
Once logged in, you can easily import
your binder constructions.
This binder contains the different pages
assembled earlier.
To navigate through it, two different
interfaces are available.
The first one uses drop-down menus,
while the second displays
the complete hierarchical tree
of the current page.
To add a pictogram to the sentence strip,
simply select it
and tap Add.
At any time, you can reorder
the sentence strip, or even
remove a pictogram by dragging
it upwards.
You can also add pictograms stored in
your local device storage, photos you
uploaded to pictotree.eu,
or directly search and pick from the
official ARASAAC pictogram bank.
With the sentence strip in full-screen mode,
you can enable the visual timer mode
on each of the cards,
and start the countdown timer.
The application is offline-first.
You have the option,
by going into the app settings,
to allow logging in without
a password.
Import and editing are then disabled,
preventing accidental changes,
and the app can be used safely
without logging in.